# Kanchi Bhawalkar

Experienced product designer & developer seeking summer internship in Front-End development/UX design, particularly in areas requiring interaction design and software prototuping.

kanchib@umich.edu

http://www.kanchib.com +734 - 747 - 3800

# **Relevant Projects**

**MPortfolio** Jan 2016 - April 2016

UX Research

Conducted needs assessment and usability evaluation of MPortfolio website using qualitative and quantitative research methods with an aim of increasing its outreach and cater to a wider user base.

Conducted user interviews to understand user behavior, motivations & attitudes, subsequently mapped the same to user personas and scenarios.

Created an interaction map and conducted comparative analysis, user surveys, heuristic evaluation and usability testing to generate key findings and propose recommendations & best practices.

Fix It Sep 2015 - Dec 2015

Interaction Design

Conceptualized and designed a mobile application to facilitate tenant landlord communication.

Conducted user surveys to design personas, created storyboards, wireframes, paper prototypes and interactive digital prototype.

Washable Jan 2016 - April 2016

Physical Product Design / Rapid Prototyping

Conceptualized, designed and built a brush to enable one-handed people wash and scrub their hand.

Worked through the process of market research, concept generation and selection, technical development, production process design, pricing, inventory stocking and advertising for the product. Designed and developed a promotional website for the product.

Modeled and built the product iteratively using Rhino and 3D printing

# Services to Enhance Potential

Jan 2016 - April 2016

Contextual Inquiry

Conducted user interviews to understand the flow of information related to performance measurement and evaluation of trainees

Created an affinity diagram to identify flaws in the current information flow within the system & gave recommendations to correct the same.

#### ECG Anomaly Detector - Ashwinee Healthcare

June 2011 - June 2012

User Interface Design and Development - Mobile Application

Designed and developed the user-interface for an Android application to detect fast heart rate, slow heart rate and 4 other heart - related anomalies.

#### **Relevant Coursework**

Introduction to Interaction Design, Fundamentals of Human Behavior, Graphic Design, Contextual Inquiry, Usability & Needs Evaluation, Design of Complex Websites, Integrated Product Development, Object Oriented Modeling and Design, Advanced Database Management Systems

# **Organizations**

**Education** 

University of Michigan - Ann Arbor MS Information in Human-computer Interaction

University of Pune, Maharashtra, India Aug 2008-June 2012 Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

# **Work Experience - Development**

#### TIBCO Software, Pune, India

July 2012 - July 2015

May 2017

Associate Member Technical Staff - Product Design & Development

Analyzed and researched HTTP protocol standards in depth to develop new enhancements for TIBCO Activematrix Businessworks enterprise integration platform as well as subsequently stabilized and improved its performance.

Conducted background research, outlined product requirements and determined data flow for TIBCO Expresso mobile integration platform which leveraged the power of event driven consumable APIs.

Spearheaded design and development of an SDK and a RESTful server using Jersey & Jetty for TIBCO Expresso.

## Digital Education and Innovation Group, University of Michigan

Feb 2016 - Present

Research Assistant - Full stack development

Developing a puthon based XML parsing tool to aid the migration of guizzes from Coursera to edX.

# **Work Experience - User Experience**

## Design Clinic, University of Michigan School of Information

Feb 2016 - Present

UX Consultant - Visual & Interaction design

Conducted extensive ideation and brainstorming along with comparative analysis of several MOOC's and video-sharing websites to design the overall user experience of the Entrepreneurship Greenhouse website.

Designed the style guide, wireframes, Low-Fi (paper prototypes), Hi-Fi mockups and interactive prototypes for the website.

### University of Michigan Library

Feb 2016 - Present

Visualization Consultant

Working as a user interface designer and front-end web developer to realize data visualizations using HTML, CSS &

#### **Creative Skills**

Wireframing, Prototyping, User Interviews, Personas, Usability Testing, Surveys, Comparative Analysis, Heuristic Evaluation, Affinity Diagrams, Illustrator, Photoshop, Lightroom, Invision, Sketch, Principle UI, Keynote, iMovie.

## **Technical Skills**

HTML/CSS, Javascript, Java, REST/JSON, JQuery, D3.js, Bootstrap, Puthon, Google App Engine, Web Services, Salesforce, XML, SOAP/WSDLs, Apache Maven, Git, HTTP Protocol, Android, Agile Development process.

#### Extra Curricular

Professional Photography, Theatre - Lead Sound Designer, Set Designer and Production Assistant.

Students Organization for Computer Human Interaction